Probably despawned, right?
Okay, let's go back to a safer location
and then try to get everything
back to where it should be.
You can actually check the time of night,
and it's actually becoming
daytime again, which is great.
I could actually probably
start work on the house now.
Now it's dawn.
Dawn is a beginner's trap
because there's still stuff lying around.
Yeah, I'm good, I'll pass on that.
I'll just let the sun
take care of the work.
A skeleton managed to find shade,
so we're just gonna have to do
the rest the work ourselves.
Alright, it's that.
That's the problem. They don't burn.
Everyone always falls victim to it.
They sneak up on you,
so we'll get the jump first.
I don't know if you can
sneak up on mobs in this game,
like if that's a thing that works.
I'm pretty sure it doesn't,
especially when someone's
trying to sneak up on me.
Yeah, okay.
I'm good.
I don't need you to blow up.
I'm alright.
That wasn't too difficult.
There was one lying around over there.
Oh boy, they're everywhere.
They're like hiding in the forest.
Look, there's two here.
Oh my goodness.
Alright, here we go.
Another one.
I really don't want it to blow up
because that would be really frustrating.
I hate filling in creeper holes,
and I don't like leaving them either,
so it's just a lose-lose situation.
Didn't one crawl in here?
Oh, I don't like this.
Okay.
Oh yes, yep, I was right.
Careful, we gotta check our backs.
It's quite a dangerous forest today, huh?
Alright, well, I guess what I can do is
now just start kind of de-leveling.
"De-leveling"? What kind of word is that?
Leveling the forest.
What am I talking about?
These trees.
These trees are the bane of anybody's existence.
They're just a slew of problems.
Oh, and so are you.
Fighting these things is always a stress,
like, creation machine. Okay.
I could kind of start digging out
some of this grass here.
Ah, the apple.
I picked one up earlier,
but I ate it out of panic.
Right, well, golden apples can be crafted,
and if you don't know,
they heal the whole bar,
so you could be at half a heart,
and with one of those, you're back to full.
This fucker right here.
These things are a problem.
You know, cutting a tree down like this,
a lot of times you think you
might just want to set it on fire,
but you gotta be careful.
This is a game with a mod that
makes the fire go really quickly,
because that's how it was back then.
It would light things up in flames,
and it could go out of control very quickly.
And what can also happen is
lava pools can spawn in forests,
and before you know it, you look out
and the entire forest is gone.
Just disappeared.
What I want to do is put all this shit away,
because there's a ton of stuff in my inventory.
Let me also do the trick while I'm at it.
Okay, let's make some chests.
Yeah, I'll put a torch down, actually. Why not?
So, chests are fun.
This is an older version of the game.
Not really, but we're
going to pretend it is.
Now, normally, this actually shouldn't work.
This shouldn't be possible,
because this should be a full block,
but I can still do that.
That being said,
we probably should do that anyway
— treat it as if it was going to be a full block —
and not stack them on top of each other,
because if I were to update the mod,
and that were to be fixed...
It actually works on servers, by the way,
so I'm not really too sure
what's going on in single player.
But if that were to be fixed,
then our storage system is going to
be a nightmare to deal with.
You know what?
Let's actually spend the rest of the day
digging a bunch of that dirt up,
so we have a more flat place
to work with here.
So, I'm going to go do that now.
Alright, I'm kind of
running out of daylight now.
I'll plant some torches around,
to give less of a chance of things
spawning right outside my fucking door.
With that aside, let's dig up a little bit more
so we have a place to actually put stuff.
I'm going to kind of go on a
very simple system here.
Something like that, maybe.
In here, I can put food.
That goes there.
In here, I'm going to put, like,
just a bunch of blocks that I've dug up.
Y'know? Yeah, that's fine.
I'll just put the rest of a
bunch of things in here.
I'm actually going to keep my wooden pickaxe on me
because I'm going to burn it soon.
I want to take some stone out of there.
I definitely want to take some wood out of there
because it's time to go mining again.
In terms of the format of these videos,
I'm probably just going to chop them up into episodes.
I might not have an episode per play session,
so it might be a little jarring
when the video comes to a close.
But, I feel like that's
the easiest way to do it.
We're going to go take a look around.
Maybe we can hopefully find a little bit of iron
to speed up some of the process of doing...
Oh, and would you look at that!
As if on command,
it just appears right in front of me.
How excellent.
I actually want to go back
and start cooking that now, I think.
Let's just smelt it right now.
That being said, let's grab more of these
because that will help us actually get down here.
I don't like face smashers, by the way,
and I generally try to make sure
I don't make things into face smashers,
so we're just going to mine that a little bit.
Like a lot of people these days,
I do use the "torch on the wall system"
to know where I am going in a cave.
It's very efficient and very easy to do,
so that's kind of how I do it as well.
Yep, I kind of expected that.
Again, these are the worst to deal with.
Alright, we're in trouble again.
We've got to go.
We've got to— Oh my goodness!
And look what happens again.
Oh man, I can't see.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa. Okay.
What the f...
Oh no, I can't be distracted
by that right now.
I'm kind of being chased.
I see the light.
I also see a bunch of creepers.
And I also see that.
And I also see— oh, boy.
And that's what happens.
They all spawn where light is.
Also, sheep basically can't exist.
Because of this.
But, look what we can make.
Oh, he can break the door down, can't he?
Okay.
Oh, but he's just too stupid
to realize I'm in here.
What's the point of that mechanic then?
Why don't we, then, get our stuff back.
It's not too far away.
I'll never level up now,
because I just keep dying.
I didn't take much with me
in the mine, did I?
I would like to get more food, actually.
Oh, cool.
Oh, you fucker.
Didn't give me anything.
Alright, now I have something
to burn my pickaxe on.
That's the only reason I wanted that.
So, alright.
I would like to go back down in that cave,
but now I actually have: A, a better pickaxe,
and B: a better thing to actually cut with.
I only want to smelt this one,
so we'll just do that.
Okay, we'll actually take
a couple of these with us.
I don't think I brought any last time,
if I'm remembering correctly now, and uh...
That wasn't really smart, was it?
I'll keep this hardware back here.
I'm going to put all the good stuff
in that chest for now.
Alright, with that aside,
we can actually make a bed,
and most importantly,
set our spawn point.
Look at all of that wool.
Living in a forest,
we're going to see that quite a bit,
because wolves spawn,
and wolves do not like sheep.
Without further ado,
let's go and check it out.
Have you noticed that
zombies drop feathers?
Yeah, rotten flesh wasn't around.
Not that it actually matters,
because I tested it at one point,
and yeah, they poison you
when you eat them.
Oh my goodness, it's you again.
Oh, that's terrible.
So, yeah, we're going to have to get out of
this situation a little bit smart.
Oh my god, that's not smart.
Oh my goodness.
Okay.
We're in trouble.
I mean, I know I'm going to spawn...
Alright, that's one taken care of.
Ah, it's so scary.
That bow shoot noise is really loud.
A skeleton could just be
hiding anywhere right now.
This cave is very extensive at this point.
But while I'm exploring and mining,
I want to mention a couple things.
Specifically, the pickaxe that I'm using.
What the fuck is...
Is that a witch? You f...
Poison is a lot more of a problem, by the way.
Yeah, I'm going to be
brought down to half heart.
It would be smart to just wait for it to
expire before we actually heal the HP.
Well, I'm about to fucking die,
but what I was saying was this pickaxe is iron.
It's my only iron pickaxe I have.
A lot of people have the habit of saying,
"Well, I can't use it because if I come across diamonds,
I'm going to need to mine it."
Why am I going back there?
Let me just not go back there.
But the thing is,
I really think that using the faster tool,
even if you might come across diamonds
and not have it at that time, it's going to be fine.
Iron is not the rarest thing
in the game, believe it or not.
Oh, great.
I love it down here.
Everything's out to get me, isn't it?
He's coming.
Alright, we got to bail on that.
Did he not see me?
Did he fall?
I don't like this.
Okay, we got to go.
We got to go.
Yeah, this is not a good idea.
You hear that?
That's the sound of rain.
Everyone's favorite event in the game.
So we've got iron.
Beautiful.
With five iron, we can
make a blast furnace.
So let's actually do that first.
We want to just smelt it in eights,
but let's just do this.
Then we'll make a blast furnace,
that way we can have things a little quicker.
So with that, we will
make a blast furnace.
We're just going to need
that smooth... I don't need that.
Torches everywhere when you
put them in your off slot.
Can I actually use F to...?
Oh, sweet. I can.
Okay. Good shortcut to know.
We'll use that more.
Okay.
Like that. That doesn't go there.
No, it's not like that.
Like that.
That's the good stuff.
This thing will smelt it much
quicker than it did before.
So let's do that.
We could probably make
a second one if we wanted to.
Maybe I do want to, actually.
I need only two more.
How much do saplings do?
Well, we can find out.
Here, let's try.
I want to be in here.
Two per item, like sticks.
Okay.
You know, why am I doing it this way?
That was such a waste.
Oh well, we'll be okay.
Yeah, alright.
Let's make another one.
And I guess just because there's space,
we can also make another smoky.
Can you please... thank you.
Okay.
I didn't actually make the blast furnace.
I'm a mess.
Go... yes, perfect.
Yeah, look at that.
Okay.