Hello.
Welcome to Minecraft, but with a bit of a twist.
So if you look in the top left, there is a version number.
1.19.4, the latest version available at the time of recording this.
However, the title screen looks a little different, doesn't it?
This will be a playthrough of Minecraft, but I have a mod installed
that makes the game act a lot like it did, almost....
I want to say 12, 13 years ago, but it will still have a lot of the modern features.
That mod is called Nostalgic Tweaks.
It's the star of the show today.
In terms of the star of the visual design, we have a resource pack called Golden Days installed,
which brings the game back to its roots in terms of the visual design
and also takes the new stuff and tries to put it in a way that fits with the old stuff as well.
Okay, so now we're going to make a new world.
And, for this, we're going be doing hard, okay?
Now we have "Modern Beta" as our generator, which is another mod that allows us to have a beta world.
Or kind of looks like a beta world,
but it has a lot of the modern features integrated into the beta world.
And well, we just may as well hop right in and see what happens.
I got a couple other mods installed, mainly to improve the performance of the game.
There's this one which is making the chunks load quicker.
So you know, when the game opens the chunks will be shown instantly when this is done.
Anyways, we're going to hop straight into it. Now,
We can kind of see what we got. So we spawned in a desert.
Okay, now, back then you always spawned on sand.
So there is an example of actually the modern features showing up.
Alright, that wasn't around.
But if you look visually at the game, it's definitely not quite as it looks today, is it?
Lighting-wise, I turned the smooth lighting off because I felt
that would create a little more of a classic experience.
Now, in terms of what we're going
to be doing, this is not a speedrun.
I'm not going to be rushing for diamonds and rushing to kill the Ender Dragon and this, that and the other.
In terms of what this video is, it's not intended to make money. Alright?
Which means, I will not be screaming at you.
I will not have a pointless facecam in the middle of the screen.
I will not have other things that are very distracting and don't actually show...
I'm going to need a little more wood than that.
...and don't actually show, like, just things that are not, like, necessary, basically.
If you ever watch a video, like, modern day, you'll often find that
very annoyingly, there's lots of annoying effects on the screen.
They're screaming at you.
There's tons and tons of stuff, and we're not going to be doing that. Okay?
I'm just going to play the game, and I'm going to share my experience playing the game with anyone who's watching.
That being said, this will not be completely unedited, which means I will be cutting out things that are boring.
Okay.
We going to also take a quick look around, see what we got.
Now, over here appears to be a cave.
Like, with that new stuff, you can see the clay.
And if you look really closely, you can see, like,
I forget what it's called there. I haven't really played much of the new stuff, actually, for a while.
I kind of fell out of interest with this game for quite a while.
I'd only really play a bunch of complicated modpacks that,
really, at the end of the day, are just grinding the game but in a different way.
We got some beaches.
Beaches were removed from the game when 1.8 came out, and they were never fully added back in.
We have beaches with...
I'm going to put 50 quotes around them because they kind of don't really have the shape of beaches.
In terms of the video you're watching,
While I am playing the old version of the game,
I am not going to be making the video shit quality.
The video will be in 4K.
I am recording it lossless, and I will also include
closed captioning for those who have trouble hearing or understanding
English speech as much or just kind of would prefer to have them on the screen.
So I hope you appreciate that.
I think accessibility is very important, so I will definitely include those.
That being said, I'm going to go chop some wood
and when the sun starts to set, we'll see what we have to do next.
I'm also going to grab some coal here, actually, because
kind of important, you know, being able to see
we have lots of old things and that also includes the old lighting.
And the old lighting gets very dark.
If you saw earlier when I was looking into that cave,
yeah, not quite the brightest thing. Okay?
So it's going to be a little bit essential to actually have our light.
Also, I should mention the animal spawning
is going to be like old Minecraft, which means that they will spawn
where there is grass and light, including during the nighttime and daytime.
They spawn kind of like hostile mobs but in reverse: in the light, but also only on grass.
This means that farms for animals are kind of pointless because,
A: They'll actually disappear, from what I understand.
Like, the ones that don't disappear are, like, the named ones,
and, like, tamed animals.
But even if you breed them, I'm pretty sure they despawn,
which kind of makes farming a little bit pointless for the most part.
That being said, food is, at that point, going to be a lot easier to get.
But those of you who have been looking may have noticed that there's no hunger bar.
Now, those who have played Minecraft in its earlier days
knows why this is the case: because it wasn't a thing at that point.
Instead, the function food served was specifically for healing. And not only for healing,
but your health did not naturally regenerate like it does today,
which means that if you take damage, then that damage stays until you heal it again.
But that also means that if you don't take damage, you don't have to eat either.
So bearing that in mind, it's kind of a different balance
than the hunger system, which is more of an active problem.
And you have to keep it at bay and manage it, basically.
Whereas, back then you didn't really have to manage it, but you can lose your health very fast.
The upside is that you can heal very quickly, too.
But another downside will become apparent when I'm going to kill some of these animals here.
Actually, there's two of them. The first one...
Okay. Drops nothing. The usual.
You may notice that these drops aren't quite the same. Well,
if I remember correctly, I think in modern versions there's a guaranteed food drop since animals are a lot more rare.
Back then, though, the drop had a chance of being zero.
Now watch.
If you notice, they don't stack. Food does not really stack back then.
Okay?
So that means that while you can heal very fast, you have to actually have the inventory space for the food.
And, taking up one slot per single food item, you really can't afford to spend that much of your inventory on food.
If you're listening, you may hear reverb.
Yep. I decided to install Sound Physics too, because just kind of for fun, more or less.
It's not really very old Minecrafty, but it's not as if new Minecraft has sound physics either, really.
So I figured there'd be no harm in something a little fun like that.
But yeah, it's mostly going to be a vanilla experience apart from that.
Right, so I should also mention the second issue when it comes to food.
So as you can see, first of all, it might not drop nearly as often,
but I want you to kind of watch carefully as I kill the next set of animals.
So you may have been able to figure it out, but from these cows, I'm only getting leather.
From these chickens, I'm only getting feathers.
That's because back then that was the only food-dropping animal we had.
So bearing that in mind, the main food source is pork chops.
Technically, beef, chicken, mutton -- they're all still in the game -- but unless they appear, like,
in some kind of loot table or, like, a chest or something, it's not really going to be obtainable.
Not that it really matters too much.
Pork is plenty fine.
So we've kind of stocked up on a good amount of food,
and, if you see, we've got a good amount of wood -- the sun is setting.
So, I want to build a real house.
But there's kind of not a lot of time for that.
You can't really sprint away from mobs anymore because
I have not been sprinting not because I don't feel like it, but because there is no sprinting.
So, I'm going to need to seek shelter really quickly now, or I'm in trouble, basically... is the problem.
So, we could do what we always did and carve into the side of the mountain.
I might want to find a better place to do that, actually.
That being said, I might have to stop being picky and just get inside.
Alright. We're going to go in here.
It's getting dark.
I probably should make some way to actually fucking see the game.
Okay. Yeah, I don't really bite my tongue when it comes to cursing so,
I hope that's not a problem because there's no chance I'm going to be very safe in terms of the words that I use.
Okay.
Probably should actually seal it with a door before I get creeped up on by everything in the game.
Looks very good.
So no bed at the moment.
Beds are there. We can skip the night.
I don't know if phantoms actually spawn. I'm probably going to guess that they do.
So we have to actually like utilize it or else we just get fucked by the mobs, which is kind of
definitely a thing.
And the sound physics can be a little buggy as well, but you know, what are you going to do?
So we've got an actual home now.
You can kind of light up the outside, but again, it's pretty dangerous out there right now.
You may have noticed, but the difficulty is not on easy or normal. It's on hard.
So we can get slaughtered very quickly early game.
The first night's not going to be super interesting.
So I'm probably just going to go mining for the first night
and start trying to cook these at the same time.
I might start a staircase from here.
Ah, you hear that sound?
That's the sound of monsters.
And you can hear... oh, yeah.
Okay, this is a problem.
I have no armor. I have leather, I can make something.
It won't really get me much.
We'll do a helmet. Sure. Let's do that.
Again, that's basically nothing if you look at the bar.
I'm also not really being very efficient with this.
But, you know, what are we going to do?
I guess we'll finish cooking this now.
This is going to be really good to set up with a hopper, you know, because
no stacking means I can't just load them all in, you know what I mean?
In terms of this cave, I want to explore it,
but it's really fucking dangerous.
So, we can give it a try.
Take a small look at what we've got.
That's not.
That's not a good sound. That's not a good sound.
Yeah. Okay. We've been spotted.
Oh, my god. This is not good.
Yeah,
You can see how I lost a lot of my HP very quickly there.
Right. Well, so the best I have is this little thing.
pick something that doesn't really follow the rules of gravity for a second...
Probably just abuse the AI a little bit.
Got it. All right.
See, I had it under control the whole time.
I just only mildly panicked because I had no idea what I was going to do when I was getting shot at.
But, as you can see, it all works out in the end.
That being said,
Okay, not a problem. I can take care of that very easily.
Really, skeletons are actually your main adversary.
Probably shouldn't be fucking around in the dark right now, but I need to make torches.
So we do have "deal" w... "deal"? Dual wielding. I'm sorry I can't talk sometimes. Okay, another one. Alright.
Oh, my god. I just replaced my sword.
Oh, this is terrible
And... there we go.
Okay. I got too cocky.
I have no idea where I ended up, but I'm gonna have to find my way back.
And this is what always happens.
In the dark, it's really bad to spawn with nothing
because I can't sprint and now I can't defend myself.
But it was kind of my fault for just diving in without really paying too much attention to my surroundings.
And also... kind of replacing the sword slot with something else was also probably not a good idea as well.
That won't be very fun. Yeah. There we go.
Maybe they won't see through the flowers.
Maybe they're too stupid to have line of sight. Oh, and they also hit a zombie.
Okay, I see that one.
It may have been over here.
It would actually be easier to find in the nighttime because of that.
Yes. Okay. We found it.
That's not good.
Unlike the old game, we have the new AI with pathfinding, so.
Okay,
We've got to go.
I left no food there.
So my only chance is to just pick up my stuff.
Probably despawned, right?